Mikeg1804@gmail.com

(404) 901 4180

SUMMARY

Driven and proven senior executive with over 17 years of progressive experience working in private equity, venture capital, and public companies. Proven strategic thinker and experienced in putting in place effective performance indicators to drive results. Experienced in running operations, budgeting, forecasting, building financial models for growth, and capital raising. Performed due diligence on investment opportunities. Possess strong knowledge of investment decision making, investment valuation and carry interest calculation. Possess strong management skills and business acumen to advise portfolio companies on business operations. Experienced in Mergers and acquisitions at both the transaction stage and post-acquisition transition. Possess strong quality of earnings analysis skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TRUE CAPITAL MANAGEMENT, LLC., San Francisco, CA

2019-Present

Executive Team Member

Co-lead fast-growing asset management firm with \$2 Billion Assets Under Management (AUM) offering multiple investment products, including venture, real estate funds and wealth management. Firm has 44 employees in various functions. Co-led several mergers & acquisitions (M&A) and post-acquisition integration of target. Co-lead strategic direction of firm, impacting multiple areas, including revenue growth, marketing approach, effective training, and personnel issues. Lead revenue and growth forecasts for firm using bottom-up approach, working with strong personality wealth advisors.

- Developed and co-executed five-year growth plan for company based on acquisitions and organic growth
- Grew AUM from \$1 Billion to \$2 Billion in three years
- Grew Revenue from \$10.2 Million to \$18 Million in three years
- Developed effective compensation plans to motivate advisors to grow revenue
- Co-led sell side due diligence to sell significant portion of firm to external investors
- Co-led buy side due diligence to acquire subsidiary

Chief Financial Officer & Valuation Committee Member

Oversee finance of 80 entities, including 52 funds covering various strategies to different types of LPs. Vehicles included mostly direct investments and few fund of funds. Some funds are structured as pool vehicles and special purpose vehicles (SPV) for single investment holdings.

- Co-led structuring transaction for overseas acquisitions, including dealing with tax issues in Spain and Portugal
- Designed processes and policies to ensure efficient running of finance department, leveraging technology and templates
- Created valuation policy
- Perform valuation analysis of venture stage companies based on latest round of financing, comparable companies'
 current value & transactions, and other qualitative evaluation of performance and management updates. Allocated
 valuation based on different series of rounds with different rights
- Perform timely and accurate carry interest calculation
- Hire, train, and mentor successful employees
- Manage relationship with external auditors, tax advisors and fund administrators for outsourced funds
- Ensured proper accounting and reporting for crypto fund with multiple side pockets
- Obtained unqualified opinions on all fund audits

TRUE CAPITAL MANAGEMENT, LLC., San Francisco, CA

2019-Present

Investment & Venture Committee Member

Co-lead investment decision making on venture stage companies based on presentations from due diligence team.

- Co-founded True Culture Fund, which included partnership with Y Combinator for proprietary deal flow
- Achieved 67.3% and 74.4% IRR Net of fees in funds
- Co-lead efforts on investment asset allocation and rebalancing for wealth management investors
- Detail review due diligence materials on investment opportunities by junior associates for True Culture fund

Chief Financial Officer of Spain Fitness Venture (DBA CR7 by Crunch)

Oversee finance of portfolio company, fast-growing gym chain, generating €4 Million annual revenue, offering low-cost gym memberships in Spain and Portugal, and offering soccer fans way to connect with World's most popular soccer star.

- Built financial model resulted in acquisitions, growing business from two to 14 locations
- Co-led sell side capital raising efforts to power growth, including bridge financing rounds
- Maintain cap table and financial projections for capital raise
- Lead investment bank to create pitch decks for capital raise
- Maintain monthly financial forecasts for operations
- Grew revenue from \$1.9 Million to \$3.9 Million in two years

Chief Financial Officer of Illusion Technology

Oversaw finance of seed stage portfolio company, with rights to sell Proto units in large major cities, like Las Vegas, New York, and Tokyo. Company was set up to manage business and commercial side of Proto (formerly PortL), "A" round stage company that makes holograms. Company was later acquired and consolidated into Proto.

- Built financial models to support business plan from inception
- Co-led effort to write business plan and strategies for company
- Co-led effort to create gym app and other software applications to be used within newly invented Proto units

CANYON BRIDGE CAPITAL PARTNERS, INC., Palo Alto, CA

2017-2019

Chief Accounting Officer and Vice President of Finance

Oversaw finance of private equity firm with \$1.5 Billion AUM. Managed risks and strategic financial direction of firm. Managed short-term cash and treasury investments to enhance returns and profitability. Created budget and monitored budget to actual performance for timely corrective actions. Reviewed and approved financial transactions and implemented controls to improve operations and quality. Oversaw financial reporting under SEC rules. Managed relationships with Deloitte and other significant third-party service providers. Managed cross-cultural operations with part of team in China.

- Put in place financial accounting system for multiple entities, including foreign subsidiaries
- Worked with Deloitte to devise tax strategy to defer taxes for three years to enhance cash flow
- Aligned timeline of incoming cash flow against expenses for smooth operations
- Worked with third party consulting firm to improve transfer pricing agreement among various related parties within firm
- Negotiated significant professional fees discount with outside vendors to improve cash flow
- Worked on valuation of venture and private equity investments, using option pricing model and income and market approaches
- Served as acting CFO for Imagination Technologies for two months in between change in leadership

ERNST & YOUNG, LLP., San Francisco, CA

2011-2017

Manager

Led efficient simultaneous execution of several audits of private equity (PE) and hedge fund entities. Spent significant time working on investment valuation for PEs, based on various models, including Leverage Buyout (LBO), Discounted Cash Flow (DCF), Comparable Company Analysis (CCA) and Comparable Transaction Analysis (CTA). Worked on valuation of distressed debts. Notable clients included Hellman & Friedman (\$80 Billion AUM), Genstar Capital Partners (\$35 Billion AUM), and Farallon Capital (\$39 Billion AUM).

- Outsourced work to India to increase engagement profitability
- Managed and Resolved conflicts between clients and engagement teams

Senior Associate

Led efficient execution of SunTrust Robinson Humphrey (significant investment banking and broker dealer subsidiary of SunTrust Banks) audit. Led effort to significantly improve quality from prior year by setting expectations and providing ongoing weekly coaching to enforce promulgated firm guidance. Developed successful staff by providing ongoing feedback and guidance on successful problem solving. Successfully managed relationship with senior client executives to obtain timely support to perform audit. Provided assurance services to publicly traded fortune 500 asset management firm (Invesco) with \$700 Billion of AUM and several domestic and foreign held subsidiaries and other complex investment vehicles (i.e., variable interest entities (VIEs)) and voting interest entities (VOEs)). Client's portfolio comprised of several funds, offering various investment products, including collateralized loan obligations (CLOs), private equities, and other consolidated investment products (CIPs). Worked on timberland real estate funds, which involved testing valuation of complex level 3 assets. Worked on due diligence for M&A targets for three months rotation in EY M&A group.

- Received significantly exceeded expectation rating
- Trained and developed others to become high performing staff
- Received compliments from audit clients for professionalism and effective management of engagement relationship
- Inspired trust out of team by providing guidance on the operations and ways to audit complex areas of consolidated investment products, goodwill and intangible impairment testing, and broker dealer regulatory compliance calculations

SUNTRUST BANKS, INC., Tallahassee, FL

2008-2009

Commercial Banking Associate

Oversaw portfolio of 150 business clients generating up to \$100 Million in revenue and \$2.5 Million in total banking exposure. Reported directly to Senior Vice President of commercial banking. Underwrote and presented commercial credit packages to senior credit executives. Underwriting process included due diligence, interviews of senior executives (e.g., CEOs and CFOs) and analysis of financial statements of emerging and middle market companies.

- Received SunTrust's due diligence training
- Underwrote \$3 Million government backed commercial real estate deal for local hospital and \$1.3 Million airplane lease deal for McDonald's supplier, both deals required setting up interest rate swaps

WIRELESS ADVOCATES, LLC., Orlando, FL

2005-2007

Retail Sales & Operations Manager

Led operation of small business. Duties included hiring and developing high performing associates to meet aggressive monthly sales quotas.

- Exceeded monthly quota by 121%
- Received handwritten recognition letter from company president for location growth and performance

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration concentrated in Finance

Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida

Master of Accounting concentrated in Taxation and Assurance Services

Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida

Bachelor of Science in Business Technical Management with minor in Project Management

DeVry University, Orlando, Florida

Formal Credit Underwriting Training

SunTrust University, Atlanta, Georgia

M&A Transactions, Business Valuation & Advance Excel Trainings

Wall Street Prep, San Francisco CA

OTHER

Venture Capital Investor

Created personal venture capital investment pool with thesis to invest in great companies across multiple sectors/industries, including technology (mostly software), biotech, and blockchain/crypto. Great investments are factors of quality of idea (s) or solutions venture company put forth; how those ideas can turn into products or services that is appreciated by society at large or significant market niche; amount of capital available to execute on ideas and quality of management to execute. Current portfolio of venture investments are as follows:

- Proto Hologram
- Energy Vault (Pre SPAC)
- Lime
- Dapper Lab
- Other multiple venture company exposures through other funds

Hobbies

Enjoy ballroom dancing, sports and reading.